About Me

Full name: SON, DO HONG

City: Ho Chi Minh

Phone: (+84) 963-260-895
Email: hongsondhs@gmail.com

Skype: hongsondhs **Facebook:** fb.com/sondh5

Hello I'm Son Do. I am 24 years old, based on Hanoi, now working in Ho Chi Minh city.

I graduated from FPT University Hanoi. I started web development with Ruby on Rails from September 2016. I also work as freelance web developer in Phai Team. I am a kind of extroverted and enthusiastic. I like to challenge myself and try new things.



Background



Working History

Web Developer - Zigexn VeNtura

Jan 2019 - Present

- Working in sharing economy product of company, team size 6 devs
- Shipping new features, bug-fixes in every week sprint
- Using Apache Solr as search engine
- Run application with over million products
- Updating and importing list products everyday

Web Developer - Framgia Inc.

Sep 2016 - Dec 2018

- Working in Digital Comics outsourcing project, teamsize ~30 devs
- Run product with over 2 million users (both web and native mobile app)
- Shipping new features, bug-fixes in every 2-week sprint
- Involved in building a system of 4 front servers, admin, batch, worker server
- Familiar with auto deployment with Capistrano or manually by running shell script
- Coding, review codes, improve CI/CD flow to collab with other teams
- Improve performance, have experiences in reading server log
- Develop project with Ruby on Rails as backend and other frontend related skills
- AWS products used: EC2, RDS, CloudWatch, S3, CloudFront, ELB, Route53 etc

Freelancer - Vinalign

Aug 2017 - Apr 2018

- Working in freelance project with 3 devs
- Communicate directly with the customer to define the requirement from the customer's ideas
- Involved in building a web application from zero till service in
- Run product with ~150 clinics, ~450 patients
- Familiar with auto deployment with Capistrano or manually by running shell script
- Monitoring and maintaining during a year after official release

Web Developer - FPT University

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

- Capstone project named Classy
- Description: Search and Review System for foreign language centers web-based application.

The application helps people find and compare to choose the best center for them. It also helps language centers have more students.

- Team size: 5 devs
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Hekoru Paas, jQuey, HTML/CSS

Intern - FPT Software

May 2016 - Sep 2016

- Involved in short-term on job training at FSU11.F-1
- Team size: 8 devs
- Technologies: Java Spring MVC, AngularJS, HTML/CSS
- Accomplishments: coding, teamwork, software process

Education History

Software Engineer Degree - FPT University

Sep 2013 - Dec 2017

- FPT University Talented full scholarship at Software Engineering
- Field of study: Software Engineering
- Degree rank: Good
- Certificate of completion Pearson Longman Level 6 Summit 2
- President at FU No Shy Club (English speaking and soft skill club)
- Activities and societies: English and soft skills club, Vovinam Club, Photography Club, Student council

High School Degree - Van Noi Highschool

Sep 2010 - May 2013

- Major: Maths, Physics, Chemistry
- Degree rank: Good
- Activities and societies: VN50 Team

Technical skills Ruby on Rails MySQL HTML/CSS Amazon Web Services (AWS) JavaScript/jQuery

Tools & Technologies

- ✓ Linux system (Ubuntu, macOS)
- ✓ Git version control (Github)
- ✓ Apache Solr
- ✓ Microsoft Office
- ✓ Adobe Photoshop

Languages

- ✓ English
- ✓ Japanese

Recent Freelance Projects









Achivements



Agile Fundamentals

Certificate Issuing by ICAgile Issued Jan 2018



Ruby on rails course

Certificate Issuing by Framgia Inc. Issued Oct 2016



Top 5 Social Activity Contributor

Certificate
Issuing by FPT University
Issued Spring 2015 & Summer 2015



Honor Student

Certificate
Issuing by FPT University
Issued Summer 2017